Finding Aid for Center for Russian and East European Studies (University of Michigan) records 1957-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for Russian and East European Studies (University of Michigan) records
1957-1997
1985-1993
University of Michigan. Center for Russian and East European Studies.
University of Michigan inter-disciplinary, area studies and resource center. Records relating to the administration of and the programs supported by the Center, including information on funding, courses, exchange programs, publicity, and affiliated activity. Also includes audio and video tapes of presentation and lectures.
9842 Bimu 2
8 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The records were transferred by the Center for Russian and East European Studies (donor # 8615 ) in 1997.
The collection is open for research.
The Center for Russian and East European Studies (CREES) was the product of an expansion of area studies at the University of Michigan proposed by the College of Literature, Science and the Arts (LS&A) in 1959. LS&A appointed a committee chaired by anthropology professor William Schorger to develop the proposal. The committee recommended the creation of four new centers: the Center for Chinese Studies, the Center for Russian and East European Studies, the Center for South and Southeast Asian Studies, and the Center for Near and Middle Eastern Studies. In 1961, the University secured a grant from the Ford Foundation to carry out the proposal. CREES then became designated under the National Defense Education Act (NDEA) as a center for Slavic Language and an Area Center in 1959, by the United States Office of Education. Currently, CREES remains one of only twenty-two U.S. Department of Education supported resource centers for Eastern Europe, Russia, and Central Asia.
The major goal of CREES is "to prepare a new generation of outstanding academic experts and professionals for careers in or related to our region." The center works to accomplish this goal by offering many inter-disciplinary areas of study. The center draws faculty from a variety of other departments at the university to teach courses. A few of the subjects in which students can earn their degree from CREES are business, law, journalism and education. The researcher is invited to find current information about the center at its website, located at
http://www.umich.edu/~iinet/crees/
The records for the Center for Russian and East European Studies (CREES) document an array of activities that the center has been involved with since its inception. Records from the 1980s to the 1990s make up the bulk of this record group. The documents reflect how the Center has grown and become active not just at the university level, but also at a global level. The financial, global, and business ties that CREES has worked hard to cultivate can be traced through this record group. The way those ties developed as well as the many other interests of the center will be of interest to researchers.
The records are arranged into seven series: Administrative Records, Exchange Programs, Funding, Alphabetical Files, Public Relations, Visual Material and Audio Material.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Center for Russian and East European Studies.; Soviet Union--Study and teaching.; Europe, Eastern--Study and teaching.
Genre/Form
Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Administrative Records, 1957-1997
  The series Administrative Records (1957-1997) consists of seven sub-series: Executive Committee, Inter-Center Council, Curriculum Materials, Orientation Materials, Advisory Council, Business Outreach, and Conference Materials. The sub-series Executive Committee documents the administration of CREES since it was founded. Of special interest to the researcher will be the history of the center. The Inter-Center Council was made up of representatives from all of the area centers. Its concern was how all of the centers should work together at the university. Curriculum Materials contains many bibliographies that were used for the courses that were taught. Orientation Materials are the records of a series of orientations that CREES held in conjunction with the Business School for people who were traveling to Russia or East European countries. They introduced people to a basic history of the country, the current political and social situation of the country and the culture of the country. Business Outreach and Advisory Council documents CREES's interest in making ties to the business community. Business Outreach covers the earlier, initial phase of the program, while Advisory Council is the official name that was given to the program once it became an established part of the center. The final sub-series, Conference Materials, documents the planning that went into many of the conferences that CREES sponsored.
  - Executive Committee
    - Agendas, 1959-1993; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Budget, 1965-1992 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1993; 7 folders (Box 1)
    - Curriculum Proposals, 1972-1992 (Box 1)
    - Grant Applications, 1966; 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - History, 1960; 1993 (Box 1)
    - Memorandums, 1957-1993; 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1992 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1961-1993; 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1968-1988 (Box 1)
  - Inter-Center Council
    - Area Studies, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - External Review, circa 1971-1986 (Box 2)
    - Foreign Area Studies Advisory Committee (FASAC), 1981-1990 (Box 2)
    - History of the Center, 1959-1990 (Box 2)
    - Joint Programs, 1981-1986 (Box 2)
    - Memorandums, 1962-1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1962-1992 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1989 (Box 2)
  - Title VI Curriculum Materials, 1991
    - Courses (Box 2)
    - Courses Offered (Box 2)
    - 310, "Yugoslavia in the 1980s,", Winter 1984 (Box 2)
    - 310, "Arms Control and the Soviet Union,", Winter 1985 (Box 2)
    - 312, "Contemporary Poland,", Fall 1982 (Box 2)
    - 312, "Soviet Media,", Winter 1987 (Box 2)
    - 316, "Marxism and Religion in Eastern Europe,", Fall 1988 (Box 2)
    - 320, "Lina Kostenko and the Ukrainian Cultural Renaissance,", Winter 1990 (Box 2)
    - 333, "Soviet and East European Media,", Fall 1987 (Box 2)
    - 395, "Survey of the Soviet Union and Successor States,", Spring 1992; Fall 1994; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 396, "Survey of Eastern Europe,", Spring 1990; 1991 (Box 2)
    - 396, "Survey of East-Central Europe,", Winter 1995 (Box 2)
    - 410, "Contemporary European Migrations,", Fall 1978 (Box 2)
    - 411, "The Realm of Ideas in East European and Russian Literature,", Winter 1973 (Box 2)
    - 411, "Succession Crisis East and West,", Winter 1975 (Box 2)
    - 412, "American Culture: A View from Outside,", Fall 1973 (Box 2)
    - 414, "The Coming European Security Conference,", Winter 1973 (Box 2)
    - 418, "Human Rights in the USSR and Eastern Europe,", Winter 1978 (Box 2)
    - 420, "Non-Russian Nationalities of the USSR,", Winter 1974 (Box 2)
    - 488, "Social Surveys in the USSR,", Fall 1989 (Box 2)
    - Course Packets (Box 2)
    - "Contemporary Eastern Europe,", Fall 1983 (Box 2)
    - "On Soviet Media,", Winter 1987 (Box 2)
    - "Revolutions in Eastern Europe: The Beginning of the Post-Communist Era", circa 1990 (Box 2)
    - "Soviet Culture Under Gorbachev,", Winter 1989 (Box 2)
    - "The Unfinished Revolutions in Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union,", March 1991 (Box 2)
    - "The USSR Today,", Fall 1984 (Box 2)
    - "Untitled," Evaluations, Fall 1986 (Box 2)
    - Course 395, Fall 1991 (Box 2)
    - Course 395, Spring 1992 (Box 2)
    - Course 395, Fall 1993 (Box 2)
    - Course 396, Spring 1991 (Box 2)
    - Course 396, Winter 1993 (Box 2)
    - Course 396, Winter 1994 (Box 2)
    - Course 396, section 001, Winter 1991 (Box 2)
    - Course 396, section 002, Winter 1992 (Box 2)
    - Course 396, section 003, Winter 1992 (Box 2)
    - Polish Business Courses, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
    - Seminar for Teachers, 1985-1986; 1992 (Box 2)
    - Seminar for Teachers, "Whither the New World Order in Eastern Europe and the Former Soviet Union?,", 1993 (Box 2)
    - Summer Institute for Teachers, "Global Environmental Health Challenges of the 1990s,", 1995 (Box 2)
    - Symposium for Teachers, "Cross-Cultural Perspectives on Gender,", 1994 (Box 2)
    - Un-Numbered Mini-Course, "Cultural Renaissance in the USSR or Age of Disillusion?", Winter 1992 (Box 2)
    - Workshop, "Understanding Soviet Communism as a Civilization", circa 1982 (Box 2)
    - Workshop for Teachers, "New Nations and New Relations in the Post-Cold War World,", 1995 (Box 2)
    - Workshop for Teachers, "Eastern Europe and the Former Soviet Union,", 1996 (Box 2)
    - Workshop for Teachers, "Global Education: World Cities,", 1997 (Box 2)
  - Orientation Materials
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
    - Czech Program, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Film List, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Hungarian Program, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
    - Polish Program, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Program Budgets, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Program Evaluations, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Program Faculty, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Program Publicity, 1994 (Box 2)
    - "Russia: A Difficult Way to a Market Economy," Evaluations, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Russia Program, Evaluations, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Russia Program, Notes, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Russia Program, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Slovak Program, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Advisory Council
    - Administrative Materials, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
    - Berliner, Jr., Harry, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
    - Mailing Lists, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
    - Meeting Evaluations, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 3)
    - Vincent, Robert, 1986-1989 (Box 3)
  - Business Outreach
    - Administrative Materials, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
    - Automotive Seminar Phone Calls, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 3)
    - Development Meetings, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Dworkin, Carol, Business Contacts Correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
    - Plan-Econ, Evaluations, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Travel Seminar, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Yugo America, Inc., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Conference Materials
    - Bellagio, Italy, 1979 (Box 3)
    - "Culture and its Social Context: the Case of Dmitri Shostakovich,", 1987-1989 (Box 3)
    - "Economic Reform in Eastern Europe,", 1968-1970 (Box 3)
    - Faculty Enrichment Program, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Faculty Enrichment Program, Bibliography, 1984-1987 (Box 3)
    - "Influence of eastern Europe and Western Areas of USSR on Soviet Society,", 1970 (Box 3)
    - International Communism Conference II, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Library Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Briefing on Soviet Affairs, 1984-1986 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Briefing on Soviet Affairs Dinner, 1986-1990 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1990 (Box 3)
    - Poland's International Debt Symposium, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Poland's International Debt Symposium, Papers, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Popular Front Symposium, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Quebec Conference, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Religion Conference, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
    - Religion Conference, Papers, 1986-1989; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Rockefeller Conference, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Russian Arts Festival, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Soviet Emigre Research Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
    - Soviet Ethnic Relations Conference, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Soviet Foreign Policy Conference, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
    - Soviet Labor Conference, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Windows into Russia, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Yiddish Festival, 1976-1981 (Box 3)
- Exchange Programs, 1987-1997
  Exchange Programs (1987-1997), the second series consists of three sub-series: American Collegiate Consortium (ACC), Graduate Exchange Programs and Miscellaneous Exchange Programs. Of special interest are the letters that some of the participants in the ACC wrote to CREES about the experiences that they were having in Russia. All of the correspondence with the universities in Russia are interesting because they show how closely the two sides had to work together to make the exchange program a success. The researcher should be warned that some of the correspondence is written in Russian with no available translation.
  - American Collegiate Consortium
    - Agreements, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1996; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Guide to the Program, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1989-1996 (Box 4)
    - Orientation Handbook, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
    - Participants-American, 1989-1996; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Participants-Russian, 1989-1996; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Graduate Exchange Program
    - Agreements-In English, 1990-1993 (Box 4)
    - Agreements-In Russian, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
    - Avaliani, Nana, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1994; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, In Russian, 1990-1994 (Box 4)
    - Hrystak, Yaroslav, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1995 (Box 4)
    - Lomagin, Nikita, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Scvortsova, Alla, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
    - Zaslavskya, Tatiana, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Exchange Programs
    - Citizens Exchange Council, Agreements, Handbook, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - Citizens Exchange Council, Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
    - Lviv Exchange Program, Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 4)
- Funding, 1961-1995
  The series Funding (1961-1995) is composed of the proposals that CREES wrote to acquire funding for their programs. Of interest are the wide variety of sources to which CREES appealed, such as the federal government, the Corporation for Public Broadcasting and many private foundations. The wide variety of programs which CREES was is apparent.
  - Antonovych Foundation Proposal, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
  - Bradley Foundation Proposal, Correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 4)
  - Bureau of Higher and Continuing Education, Performance Report, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Bureau of Post-Secondary Education, Performance Report, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation and the MacArthur Foundation, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation Proposal, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, Proposal, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1983-1994 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Research, Rackham-William Rosenberg, Grant, 1984-1987 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1961-1971 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1961; 1967 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1971; 1986 (Box 5)
  - Proposal, 1965-1990; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Proposal "A Five-Year Program of the Center for Research on Conflict Resolutions,", 1961 (Box 5)
  - Proposal "A Ten-Year Development Program in Chinese Studies,", 1961 (Box 5)
  - Proposal, "A Ten-Year Development Program in Russian Studies,", 1961 (Box 5)
  - Proposal "A Ten-Year Development Program in Southern Asian Studies,", 1961 (Box 5)
  - Proposal, "Summary Report,", 1965-1974 (Box 5)
  - Proposal, "Summary Statement,", 1961 (Box 5)
  - Foundations Lists (Box 5)
  - Greve Foundation, Budget, 1986-1988 (Box 5)
  - Greve Foundation, Proposal, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Greve Foundation, Proposal, 1989 (Box 5)
  - H. Smith Richardson Charitable Trust Grant, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - International Research and Exchange Board Grant, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Kellogg Foundation, Proposal, 1986; 1991 (Box 5)
  - Lilly Endowment, Proposal, 1986 (Box 5)
  - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Mellon Foundation, 1979-1987 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Council for the Arts
    - 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - 1987 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Council for the Humanities, Grant Proposal, 1979-1987; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Mott Foundation, 1977-1984; 1992 (Box 5)
  - National Council for Soviet and East European Research, Proposals, 1981-1991 (Box 5)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, Proposal, 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, Proposals, 1983-1995; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, Proposal, 1991 (Box 5)
  - National Institute of Education, 1980 (Box 5)
  - National Security Education Office, Proposal, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Olin Foundation, Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 5)
  - Proctor and Gamble, Proposal, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Proposal for the continuation of the Center, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Proposal for continuation of the East Asian Language and Area Center, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Proposal for the continuation of the Near Eastern Studies Language and Area Center, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Proposal for the continuation of the South and Southeast Asian Language and Area Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Proposal, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Sarah Scaife Foundation Proposal, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Social Science Research Council Proposal, 1986-1987; 1991; 1994 (Box 6)
  - United States Department of Education (Box 6)
  - Performance Report, 1973-1991; 11 folders (Box 6)
  - Proposal, 1981-1994; 11 folders (Box 6)
  - Proposal Survey, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Title VI Proposal, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Title VI, Reports, Evaluations, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Title VI, Review, 1993 (Box 6)
  - United States Department of State, Research Proposals, circa 1985 (Box 7)
  - United States Information Agency University Affiliations Program, Proposal, 1991-1993; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - United States Institute of Peace, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - United States Institute of Peace, Performance Report, 1991 (Box 7)
  - United States Institute of Peace, Proposals, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - University College London, Proposal, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - University Council on International Academic Affairs, 1991 (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan Slavic Language and Area Center Performance Report, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- Alphabetical Files, 1974-1995
  The fourth series, Alphabetical Files (1974-1995), contains files arranged in alphabetical order by the subject to which they pertain. Many of the original subject headings that CREES used have been maintained. The bulk of the folders cover the time period of the early 1990s. The majority of folders deal with topics that do not appear anywhere else in the record group. Of note are the folders about the International Institute, especially about the development of the institute and plans for its new building.
  - Abt Associates, Inc., 1995 (Box 7)
  - Alumni Association Trip, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Archives-Russia/CREES Projects, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Armenian Studies / Manoogian Foundation, 1980-1995 (Box 7)
  - Baltics, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Beidina, Oksana, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Burnham, William, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Business Records, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Central Asian Symposium, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Chamberlin, Calvin, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Center for International Business Education, 1993 (Box 7)
  - CSFR, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Center for Research Learning and Technology, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Davidson Institute: Instructional Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Davidson Institute: Edward Snyder, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Development, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Director's Letters, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
  - Duderstadt Meeting, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Freedom Forum: Lviv, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Fund Drive Agreements, 1989-1994 (Box 7)
  - Funding, 1983; 1988; 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Indiana-Michigan Series, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Industries, Russia, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Institute of Public Policy Studies, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Institute for Social Research, 1992 (Box 7)
  - International Institute (Box 7)
  - Administrative Material, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Annual Review, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Building, Library, 1994 (Box 7)
  - General Information, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Meetings, Minutes, 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Inter-Unit Programs, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Islam Seminar, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Jeszenszky, Giza, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Journalism Project, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Kauffman, Bill, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Language Instruction, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Praeger Publishers, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - National Security Education Program, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Plans for a Center Brochure, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - Po, 1991-1992; 1995 (Box 7)
  - Post-Soviet Committee, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
  - Rossiiski Nezavisimyi Institute, circa 1991 (Box 7)
  - School of Natural Resources and the Environment (SNRE), 1993-1995 (Box 7)
  - Slavic Department, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Social Work in Russia, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Soviet Text Translation Project-Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Soviet Text Translation Project-Appendix, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Summer Language Institute, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Syktyvkar, Noril'sk, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Tol'yatti Politechnical Institute, 1993 (Box 7)
  - United States Department of Education Meeting, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Washington, D.C. U of M office, 1993 (Box 7)
  - WTVS-Poland Show, 1993 (Box 7)
- Public Relations, 1961-1995
  The series Public Relations (1961-1995) is composed of clippings and press releases that CREES had accumulated since its inception. They pertain to activities and interests that directly regarded CREES. Of special interest to the researcher are the clippings for "Michigan Briefing," held in 1986, which document the CREES conference focused on the evolving status the Soviet Union at the time.
  - Press Releases, 1961-1995 (Box 8)
  - Clippings, 1961-1990; undated; 4 folders (Box 8)
- Visual Material
  The series Visual Material (ca. 1980s-1990s) contains video and cassette tapes of lectures given at the University of Michigan on various areas of research in Russian and East European Studies. In addition to these taped lectures, the researcher should pay special attention to the tapes of Russian television programs(in Russian). They contain images of Moscow and other areas of Russia. Another tape that may interest the researcher is the American Collegiate Consortium tape, which describes the undergraduate exchange program involving U-M and Russian students. There are no transcripts or translations for any of the video tapes.
  - VHS Video Tapes
    - Address Marking the 70th Anniversary of the October Revolution Parade through Red Square by Mikhail Gorbachev (Box 8)
      (In Russian)
    - American Collegiate Consortium: Lasting Connections-Real Participation New Places and Peoples (Box 8)
    - "Current Re-writing of History in Soviet Society"-Lecture by Vera Tolz, 1988 (Box 8)
    - "Evolution and Development of the Soviet General Staff"-Lecture by Professor Rice at the University of Michigan, 1987 (Box 8)
    - "Glasnost and Soviet Politics"-Lecture by Alexander Zinoviev at the University of Michigan, 1987 (Box 8)
    - "Meritocracy and Equality Under Gorbachev"-Lecture by Walter Conner at the University of Michigan, 1987 (Box 8)
    - "New Trends in Soviet TV"-Lecture by Yurri Poliskii, 1988 (Box 8)
    - PICAS Sample Tape of Soviet Television (Box 8)
    - "70th Anniversary of the October Revolution Parade Through Red Square" (Box 8)
    - Sobchak, Anatoly, Press Conference at Rackham, February 28 1995 (Box 8)
      (In Russian with a translator)
    - "Soviet Media Treatment of Lennin's Period of Power"-Lecture by Vera Tolz at the University of Michigan (Box 8)
      (The tape is labeled "Vera Tolz-1st Talk)
    - "Soviet Policy in the Gorbachev Era" Lecture by Walter Connor at the University of Michigan, October 21, 1987 (Box 8)
    - "The Winds of Change: Old Systems in a State of Flux" A Symposium held at Rackham Hall on, January 28, 1988 (Box 8)
      Speakers were: Lemual Johnson, Michael Oksenberg, John Campbell, Jill Crystal, Nicholas Dirks, Linda Lim, and Roman Szporluk
- Audio Materials
  The final series Audio Material includes both cassettes and micro-cassettes of lectures given by researchers in the field of Russian and East European Studies.
  - Cassette Tapes
    - Hewitt, Ed A. "Gorbachev's Reforms: Their Implications for East-West Economic Relations" a lecture at the University of Michigan, December 1, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Shoup, Paul "Yugoslavia" a lecture on WUOM (Box 8)
      (the University of Michigan's Public Radio Station)